Software Engineer

HWEE SHAN WONG

→ hweeshan wong@hotmail.com

+44 7424 586 826

HweeWong

EXPERIENCE

Natwest Group, Edinburgh

Software Engineer | since April 2018

[{ "item": "• Automated the onboarding process to developer tools. Reduced cycle time from 48 hrs to 5 mins." }, { "item": "• Delivered Spring Boot Java microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the system design." }, { "item": "• Actively engaged in system design decisions/architecture. Collaborated closely with customers/SMEs in agile development." }, { "item": "• Cultivated behaviour-driven and test-driven development within the team which enhanced system reliability and team's devops metrics. KPI - 50% reduction in software development cycle time." }, { "item": "• Drove infrastructure and tooling improvements. Presented proof of concepts for various authentication/authorisation modules for tools." }, { "item": "• Mentoring junior engineers and continuously building best practices within the team such as codifying workflow using plantuml." }]

Natwest Group, Edinburgh

Technology Service Analyst | Sep 2017 – Apr 2018

[{ "item": "• Responsible for migrating server data from bespoke tools to standardised ServiceNow Configuration Management Database for better consolidation of enterprise data." }, { "item": "• Automated data gathering and validation process for the migration work to make sure data quality was high and consistent." }, { "item": "• Drove the implementation of agile ways of working in my team through creation of short-term, manageable goals and Kanban boards." \]

Merck, Sharp & Dohme (MSD), Newcastle

Chemical Engineer | Aug 2015 – Sep 2016

[{ "item": "• Supported technical operations in solid-dose tablet production facility and operated within GMP standards." }, { "item": "• Solved process deviations and problems by identifying root causes using Lean Six Sigma methodologies." }]

EDUCATION

First Class Honors

MEng Chemical Engineering with Industrial Experience, University **of Manchester |** Sep 2013 – Jun 2017

4A* in Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Mathematics A Levels, Taylor's College | Jan 2012 - Jun 2013

About me

Hi, my name is Hwee and currently a software engineer in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelve-factor app methodology, designing event-driven architecture and implementing infrastructure solutions and services.